你对古斯说了什么
What did you say to Gus?
他察觉到我们的行动了  没错
Because he's on to us. Yeah.
我什么都没说  你说察觉是什么意思
I didn't say Jack. What do you mean he's on to us?
他当时正朝着车走去  突然就停住了
He's walking to his car. Then suddenly he isn't.
莫非他有什么第六感不成
What, does he have some kind of sixth sense?
老天  你对他说了什么
Jesus, what did you say to him?
现在能让我问个问题吗
Could I ask my own question right now, at this point?
你是不是把炸弹带进医院来了
Did you just bring a bomb into a hospital?
怎么  我怎么能把它留在车底下
What? Was I supposed to leave it on his car?
那你就能把它带进医院  是吗
What, you're supposed to bring it into a hospital?
我的天
Oh, my God.
听着
Look.
我们在哪能找到古斯  说个地点
Where can we find Gus? Name a place.
说一个能让他出其不意
Name me one place where I could surprise him,
让他看不见我去找他的地方
where he won't see me coming.
因为他家  洗衣店
Because his house, the laundry,
餐馆  工厂化农场
the restaurant, the factory farm,
都布满了摄像头
they're all wired with cameras.
一个地方就行
One place.
好好想想
Think.
杰西  好好想想
Jesse, think.
在哪里  会是哪
Where is it? Where?
因为如果你想不出来
Because if you can't tell me,
我们就死定了
we are dead.
杰西
Jesse.
我不  我不知道
I don't-- I don't know.
也许...
Well, maybe--
打扰了  是杰西・平克曼吗
Excuse me. Jesse Pinkman?
是我
Uh, yeah.
你好  我是克莱桥警探
Hi. Detective Kalanchoe.
这位是穆恩警探  阿尔布开克警署的
This is Detective Munn, Albuquerque Police.
我们想知道能否耽误你一点时间
We were wondering if we could have a few minutes of your time,
找个地方聊一聊
maybe go someplace and talk.
聊什么
About what?
抱歉  先生  您是哪位
Sorry, sir, I didn't catch your name.
聊什么
About what?
有关布洛克・坎蒂略
It concerns Brock Cantillo
以及你对他母亲说的一番话
and a statement you made to his mother.
您何不跟我们走一趟
How about you come with us?
我们只是想了解些情况  不必紧张
We just want to clear a few things up. No big deal.
第四季 第十三集 (本季完结)
S04E13(Finale): Face Off
我被捕了吗
Am I under arrest?
不  你没被捕
No, you're not under arrest.
我们就是聊聊
We're just talking.
那如果我聊烦了
So if I get tired of talking,
想要起身走人呢
want to get up and leave--
我们希望你不要这样
We'd prefer you didn't.
你们希望
You'd prefer, so--
杰西  你为什么告诉布洛克的妈妈
Jesse, why did you tell Brock's mom
那个孩子是被下毒了
that the boy had been poisoned?
我想这件事是...
Look, I think this has been, you know,
你们怎么说来着
uh, what do you call it?
是夸大其辞  因为我的原话是
Overblown, because all I basically said was
"医生有没有想过  布洛克可能是中毒"
"Have the doctors thought maybe Brock got poisoned?"
基于全方面考虑的话
You know, in a cover-all-bases kind of sense.
当然  我肯定他们很感激
Yeah. No, I'm sure they appreciated that,
你帮他们脱离困境
you helping them out like that,
尤其是如此明确地指出了病因
especially with how specific you were and all.
蓖麻毒素  真厉害
Ricin. Wow.
是啊  蓖麻毒素  这可非同一般
Yeah, ricin-- that's definitely a big one.
可不常见
You don't see that every day,
所以当医生们听说这个
so when doctors, they hear that,
他们高度重视起来
they take it very seriously,
我们也是
as do we,
联调局的人也是
as does the FBI.
好吧
Okay.
不过挺好  你那样尽全力救助
And nice, you trying to help out like that and all,
很具职业素养
you know, professional courtesy,
分享你的专业知识
sharing your expertise.
我没什么专业的
I ain't go no expertise.
好吗  我只是...
All right? I just, you know--
你只是恰好猜到这种罕见的毒素
You just happen to guess this one rare poison
会是将这小男孩送进医院的病因
might be the thing that put this little boy in the hospital.
恭喜你  因为他的医生
And congratulations, because his doctors,
开始认为你可能是对的
they're beginning to think that you might just be right.
那你为什么猜蓖麻毒素
So why ricin?
杰西  你怎么会想到那个
Jesse, how did you come up with that?
天  我想我是
Man, I think I've--
我不清楚  一定是在《豪斯医生》
I don't know. I must've saw it
之类的电视上看到的
on House or something.
你知道的  像《豪斯医生》
Yeah, you know, like House
或者探索频道
or the Discovery Channel.
有时候你的大脑就会产生这些联想
Sometimes your brain just makes these connections.
-会吗  -我的会
- Does it? - Mine does.
这真有趣
That's interesting.
我要回去了
Look, I've got to get back.
但我们还没聊完呢
But we're still talking.
那我没被捕  但也不能离开
So I'm not under arrest, but I can't leave.
那好
So, then,
我想我该叫我的律师  对吧
I guess I should call my lawyer. Right?
我们这只是随便聊聊  杰西
We're just having a simple conversation, Jess.
继续聊聊不好吗  不要那么严肃
Why can't we keep talking, keep it light?
兄弟你可知道  凡事一遇到律师
Man, you know how it is when the lawyers get to it.
立刻就操蛋了
Suddenly everything's a big pissing match,
一贯如此
like, every time.
对抗性太强
Adversarial.
对抗性太强  然后我们就得控告你  等等
Adversarial. Then we gotta book you, blah, blah. Right?
杰西  你该知道自己是有案底的
I mean, you know. You've been around the block, Jesse.
你可不是什么好苗苗
You're no boy scout.
索尔・古德曼
Saul Goodman.
我律师
That's my guy.
是我自己打电话  还是你们打
So do I gotta call him, or do you?
你这是搞什么
What the hell do you think you're doing?
我要找索尔  现在就要见他
I need Saul. I need him right now.
那你就破门而入  破门而入
So you break into the place. You just break in!
-我的老天  -可你一直在
- Jesus! - You're here, by the way.
要是你能接个电话  应下门
If you'd had bothered answering the phone or the door,
或许我就不用...  算了
maybe I wouldn't have-- Forget it.
他在不在
Is he here?
你逗我玩呢
Is that a serious question?
他怎么会在这里
Why would he be here?
你知道他在哪儿  是不是
You know where he is, don't you?
我需要电话号码
I need a number.
听我给你说
Look. Let me explain something to you.
-我的搭档和我...  -有危险
- My partner and I... - Are in danger?
你们捅了多大的娄子
Whoop-dee-freaking-doo.
你以为他为什么不在
Why do you think he's not here?
再说这有什么稀奇的
And how's that news, exactly,
你们两个做了蠢事
the two of you being in danger,
又遇到危险
after doing something idiotic?
谁给你权力砸破我的门
And what gives you the right to break down my door?
听我说  我只需要电话号码  没别的
Look, I just need a number. Okay? That's all.
你真是烦死人了
You are such a pain in my ass.
你知道吗
You know that?
因为你的缘故  我要丢了工作
You're the reason I've got to go on unemployment
天知道什么时候能再找到
for God knows how long.
我本来盼着
I was at least looking forward
再有半小时就可以走人了
to getting out of here in the next half hour,
可是没门啊
but no!
现在我得在这等上一整天
Now I've got to wait around all day
找工人来修好这门
for a plate glass guy to come and fix this door,
谁来掏钱
and who pays for this?
好吧  这么着
Okay, you know what?
我赔你的  我来赔
Here, look. I'm giving you everything,
全算我的  成不
all of it, okay?
一  二  三
There's one, two, three--
这至少是一千七百块
Look, there's got to be at least $1,700 there, okay?
修门足够还有富余
That will more than cover the cost of the door.
我道歉
Now, I apologize profusely.
求你了  告诉我号码
Please, the phone number.
这样的门可不是一千七百块就能修好的
Door like this is going to cost way more than 1,700.
什么  不就是玻璃门吗  怎么会
What? For a plate of glass? No.
当然会  一定不止
Oh, yeah, I bet it does.
要我说  修这门至少得
I bet you it winds up costing...
两万
20,000.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
修一扇破玻璃门
Who the hell is going to charge $20,000
谁会要价两万
for a plate glass door?
哪有正经装修商...
There's no reputable vendor w--
我看现在得两万五了
Now I'm thinking 25.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
对  新墨西哥州  阿尔布开克
Yes, Albuquerque, New Mexico.
丽贝卡・西蒙斯的电话
The number of Rebecca Simmons,
内格拉・阿罗约巷306号
306 Negra Arroyo Lane.
能帮我接通吗
Would you connect it for me, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
贝姬  我是沃尔特・怀特
Becky, hi, it's Walter White.
我有...
Listen, I wa--
我...很好
I'm-I'm-- I'm fine.
很好  你怎么样
I'm fine. How are you?
那就好  那就好
Oh, good, good.
对  猫嘛...
Yes, cats are--
听我说  我和斯凯勒不在城里
Listen, Skyler and I are out of town.
我们正在去圣达菲的路上
We're on our way up to Santa Fe,
小沃尔特刚才说
and Junior just told us
他好像忘记关火炉了
that he thinks he may have left the burner on, on the stove.
对  火还着着呢
Yes, God forbid there's a fire.
所以我打电话给你
Well, that's-- that's why I'm calling.
想请你帮忙
I just wanted to ask,
真不好意思
and I'm sorry to do this,
我家的钥匙你还有吗
but do you still have the key?
还有  太好了
You do? Good.
能不能麻烦你...
And would you be willing to--
你真是我的救星
Oh, you are a life saver.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
好的  好的  我等你电话
Yes. Okay. Okay, I'll await your call.
非常感谢  再见
Thank you so much. Bye-bye.
这就对了
There you go.
贝姬
Becky?
哦  那太好了
Oh. Oh, that's good.
我就放心了
That's a relief.
这次多亏你
I owe you one, big time.
他怎么样了
So how's he doing?
你们至少得给个话
Yo, you could at least say,
别摆这副装蒜的死样子
instead of being a couple of dicks about it.
杰西  如果你对那小男孩还有一点点关心
Jesse, if you cared at all about that little boy,
就证明给我们看
prove it to me.
把你知道的都说出来
Tell us what you know.
我都说过了
I told you what I know.
再说一次
Tell us again.
干什么  以为我是祥林嫂吗
What are you, like-- like broken records?
我不过是想帮忙
I was trying to be helpful.
没别的了
End of story.
看来我们得等验毒报告出来了
Guess we'll have to wait and see what the tox screen says.
看看  还挺舒服的嘛
Oh, look at this. Isn't this cozy?
你和他们说了什么
What did you tell them?
我和他们说他们只是一群混蛋
I told them they were a couple of dicks.
真是文采飞扬
He's a wordsmith.
好了  警探们
Well, Detectives,
谢谢你们
it's been a pleasure.
现在可以走了
Now, up you go.
礼貌点
Make like you've got manners.
表现出你们对法律的尊敬
Make like you respect the rule of law.
再见[法语]  再见[德语]
Au revoir, auf Wiedersehen,
再见[西语]  快滚吧
hasta luego, get the hell out.
拜拜
Buh-bye.
就是这样  别落东西  跟上你搭档
That's it. Pick it up. Follow your partner.
限你两秒之内
And one, two...
谢谢合作
Thank you.
天呐  你们两个
Christ. You two.
要是我的菊花不幸生了息肉
All I can say is if I ever get anal polyps,
至少我知道该给他们取什么名字
I'll know what to name them.
你来带我出去的
You gonna get me out of here?
让我想想  不是的
Ah. Hm. No.
就算行也不让你出去
Not even if I could.
听着  联邦调查局会介入调查
You know, the FBI's going to show up on this ricin thing,
而在这段时间内  你将会被关在这
and then you're in it for the duration.
你得知道  你在这儿可安全着呢
You know, you're a lot safer in here.
那帮人刚还在你搭档家里守株待兔
They just tried to get your partner in his own home.
天呐
Jesus.
他没事吧
Is he okay?
暂时没事
Well, he's okay like a fruit fly's okay.
我们所剩的时日不多了
We're all on the clock here,
这真得感谢你们
and thanks for that, by the way.
你们想在老虎头上扑苍蝇
You two want to stick your wangs in a hornet's nest,
我管不了你们
it's a free country,
为什么总是我来给你们擦屁股
but how come I always gotta get sloppy seconds, huh?
而你们为我付出了什么
Have you got anything for me?
别和我说这是义务劳动
I mean, tell me I didn't poke my head up for nothing.
的确
Yeah.
我一直在考虑
I've been thinking.
结果呢
And?
卡萨・特拉奇拉
Casa Tranquila.
卡萨・特拉奇拉是什么地方
What's Casa Tranquila?
是在帕西奥・德拉诺特的一家敬老院
It's an old folks' home off Paseo Del Norte.
那孩子告诉我福林把他带到那里
Our boy tells me Fring took him there
拜访了一位病人
to visit one of the patients,
平克曼说这人你一定记得
someone Pinkman says you'll definitely remember--
迪奥・塞拉曼加
Tio Salamanca.
坐轮椅的一个老头
Old guy in a wheelchair.
不会说话
Um, doesn't talk,
只能按铃
rings a bell.
我不是说  你想到了吗
I don't mean "Does that ring a bell?"
我的意思是  那人确实只能
I mean, the guy actually has to
-按铃来交流  -我知道  我记得
- ring a bell. - I-- Yes, I know. I remember.
那又怎样  每个特定时期
So what, once every blue moon,
古斯都要去拜访一位前帮派成员
Gus goes and visits an old cartel associate.
那又能怎样
That-- That doesn't help me.
我可没法在病房里躲个半年
I can't very well hide out in a nursing home for six months,
抱着侥幸的心理希望他会来
hoping, on the off chance, that he comes back.
他们貌似并不是朋友
It's not even like they're friends.
平克曼说看上去他在折磨这老头
Pinkman said it was like he was torturing the old guy.
此话怎讲
What does that mean?
他告诉他说他的最后一个家人已经死了
He told him the last of his family was dead.
他似乎很幸灾乐祸
He seemed to enjoy telling him.
后来  平克曼问他为什么
Afterward, Pinkman asked him about it.
古斯说这个叫迪奥的人
All Gus would say was that this Tio character
曾经杀过一个和他关系很好的人
once murdered someone close to him.
等等  迪奥杀了一个和他关系很好的人
Wait. Tio murdered someone close to Gus?
我知道这并不是什么有利消息
I know it sound not particularly fruitful,
可抱歉  我只有这些信息
but, sorry, that's all I got.
他们是敌人
They're enemies,
不是朋友
not friends.
你在这游戏里的下一个数字将是
Your next number in this coverall game,
就是你盖着施莫里的地方
where you cover the whole shmoley,
是B3
is B number 3
就是金发女子和三头熊
like Goldilocks and the Three Bears.
那就是在B行里的第3个
That's number 3 in your B column,
就在O-74后面
followed by O-74.
O-74就在你卡片的另一端
That's O-74 on the other side of your card.
现在我们得到了我们下一个幸运数字  B-7
Now we have that lucky number-- B number 7.
猜到了吗  B-7
Is it lucky for you? B-7.
在I行  2-1
In the "I" Row, 2-1.
我知道你鄙视我
I know you despise me,
我也知道你想看我死掉
and I know how badly you want to see me dead,
可我愿意打赌
but I'm willing to bet
有一个人你肯定更加痛恨
that I know a man whom you hate even more.
我提供你一个复仇的机会
I am offering you an opportunity for revenge.
4-8那一块  就是美国大陆
Column 4-8, the continental United States,
不包括阿拉斯加州和夏威夷
excluding Alaska and Hawaii.
别按了  我来了
Okay, I'm here.
今早过的还好吗  塞拉曼加先生
How you doing this morning, Mr. Salamanca?
需要什么吗
You need something?
想要拉粑粑吗
You need to go poopie? Huh?
拉过粑粑了吗  拉过了
Did you go poopie already? No?
那你要什么
What do you need?
要我拿字母板过来吗
Want me to get the board for you?
好的
Okay.
好了
All right.
好了  开始吧
Okay, here we go.
A-E-I  I行
A-E-I-- Row I.
I-J-K-L-M-N
I-J-K-L-M-N--
第一个字母  N
First letter-- N.
A-E...
A-E--
E这行
Row E.
E...
E--
第二个字母是E
Second letter-- E.
A-E...
A-E--
E这行
Row E.
E...
E--
下个字母还是E
Next letter-- E.
A...  A这行
A-- Row A.
A-B-C-D-...
A-B-C-D--
下个字母是D
Next letter-- D.
A...  A这行
A-- row A.
A-B-C-D-...
A-B-C-D---
下个字母...  D
Next letter-- D.
A-E...
A-E--
E这行
Row E.
E...
E--
E
E.
A...
A--
A这行  A...
Row A. A--
下个字母是A
Next letter-- A.
A-E-I-O-U...
还没做完吧  塞拉曼加先生
I don't think we're finished, Mr. Salamanca.
A-E-I-O-U...
就这个词吗  塞拉曼加先生
Finish the word, Mr. Salamanca.
是"dear"吗  [要姑娘吗]
Is it "Dear"?
是"deal"吗  [想交易吗]
Is it "Deal"?
找毒品管制局
宝贝  "Dea"不个单词啊  [此处指毒品管制局]
Honey, "Dea" Ain't a word.
拜托别折腾我了
Help me out here.
儿子  什么事
Hey, son, what's up?
你到底什么时候过来啊
When exactly are you getting here?
我尽快
Uh, just as soon as I can.
老爸  这可不是闹着玩儿的
Look, this is a serious situation,
你怎么那么不当回事呢
and it's like you're not taking it seriously
把电话给我  我跟他说
Give me the phone. Let me talk to him.
儿子  我很当回事
No, son, I am taking it very seriously.
沃尔特  赶紧把电话给我
Just give it to me, Walt.
我很担心你姑父汉克的安危
I'm very concerned about your Uncle Hank and his safety,
不过不管是谁想害他
but whomever is making these threats against him,
我都向你保证和我绝无牵连
I can assure you there's absolutely no interest in me.
没人要算计我
I'm not on-- on anyone's radar,
-加上你和你妈  -给我  沃尔特
- and besides your mother and I. - Give it to me. Walter?
听到你儿子说什么了吗
Did you hear what he said?
赶紧过来
Get over here.
别找借口
No more excuses.
玛丽  我会尽快过去
Marie, I will be there just as soon as I can.
-我保证  -先别挂
- I promise. - Hold on.
你不一起劝劝他吗
You want to weigh in here?
没准儿你还能劝得住
Maybe you could talk some sense into him.
玛丽  他该来时自然会来  所以...
Marie, he'll get here when he gets here, so just...
好好卖你的空气清新剂去吧
Well, I hope you sell plenty of air fresheners.
最好能成为销售大王
I hope you just have a banner day over there.
沃尔特  你听着
Okay, Walt?
这里的事用不着你管
Don't worry about a thing here.
挂了
Goodbye.
也谢谢您
And thank you
"鼎力"支持
for all of your help.
有情况吗
Anything?
-大家好  -你好  史蒂夫
- Hi, everyone. - Hi, Steve.
各位还好吧
How's everybody holding up?
格米  说曹操曹操就到
Hey, Gomie, just the man I want to see.
过来看看这个
Come here, look at this.
天呐  洗衣店的事就此打住
Jesus, enough with the laundry.
别  别  听我说完
No, no, no, hear me out.
看这配电柜  要是我没弄错
This panel, if I'm reading it correctly,
就是7200安的动力
is a 7,200-amp service.
这里就装了俩
This place has two of them.
对吧
All right?
老兄  这电量可大了
That's a whole lot of juice, brother.
这规模的洗衣店一般用一半也就够了
Laundry this size typically has maybe half that, okay?
那多出那个是干什么使的
So what's with the extra panel?
你当你是托马斯・爱迪生啊
What are you, Thomas Edison now?
不  我问了好几个电工
No, I asked a bunch of electricians.
他们有自己的聊天室
They have their own chat rooms,
那地方聊的都是配电什么的
you know, like where all they talk about was wiring?
真他妈邪门  最近什么都能从网上找到
Freakin' Internet-- find anything on it these days.
你什么意见
What do you say?
既然来了  再去摸摸情况吧
Pop over, have another look-see?
听我说
Listen.
我觉得我们可能找到点线索
I think we possibly have a lead on something.
是吗
Yeah?
我们把一个家伙请进了局里
I have this guy down at the office.
他说他有些情报
He says he has some kind of information.
不过  他只肯对你一人讲
The thing is, he'll only give it to you,
面对面
in person.
行
Okay.
记着赫克托・塞拉曼加吗
Remember Hector Salamanca?
那死老头子
Sh-- Yeah.
怎么  莫非就那个敲铃铛的老瘸子
What, you mean the old cripple guy with the bell?
恐怕他那嘴比屁眼儿还紧吧
Rather crap on our floor than talk to us?
不  我干嘛要记住那个老不死的
No, I don't remember him at all. Why?
就是这个人
Well, he's the guy.
他的护理致电我们
His nurse calls us,
说他有事要谈
says he wants to powwow.
所以我们把他请到局里三个钟头
So we have this guy at the office for three hours,
可他就是要和你来谈
and he still just wants to talk to you.
想去那里  连门儿都没有
Do not even think about going down there.
玛丽
Marie.
明摆着就是个阴谋或者圈套
This is clearly a ploy or a trick or something
就是要把汉克诓到外面
designed to get Hank out into the open.
绝对如此
That's all this is.
-我们也这么想的  -说得好听
- That's what we thought. - Well.
这家伙已经金盆洗手多年了
It's been years since this guy's been a player.
他侄子也死了
His nephew's gone.
一个亲人都没有
Doesn't have anybody.
那个护士也查过了  什么都不知道
The nurse checks out-- doesn't know nothing.
完全没有头绪
Guess I just don't see an angle in it,
完全没有
if there even is one.
当然了  如果你愿意和他谈谈
Of course, if you did want to talk to this guy,
局里肯定是最安全的地方了
there's not safer place than the office.
我认为这是个坏主意
I don't think this sounds like a good idea.
我也是  汉克阿姨
Yeah, I agree, Uncle Hank.
这简直太扯了
It is a ridiculous idea,
你绝对不能去
and there is no way you are going to do it,
没得商量
end of story.
汉克  多谢你过来
Hank, thanks for coming down.
没关系  长官  很高兴见到你
No problem at all. Good to see you, sir.
塞拉曼加先生
So Mr. Salamanca.
你有话要对我说吗
You had something you want to tell me?
A  E  I  O
A-E-I-O--
O行
Row O.
P  Q  R  S
P-Q-R-S--
第一个字母是S
First letter-- S.
A  E  I  O  U
A-E-I-O-U--
第二个字母是U
Second letter-- U.
A
A--
B  C
B-C--
A  E  I
A-E-I--
J  K
J-K--
A  E  I
A-E-I--
J  K  L  M
J-K-L-M--
A  E  I  O  U
A-E-I-O-U--
U行
row U.
V  W  X  Y
V-W-X-Y--
好吧  够了
All right, that's enough.
谢谢
Thank you.
滚你...
Suck  my  ----
谢了  我会拼
Yeah, thanks. I can spell.
这就是你想说的
Well, you got that out of your system now?
要再试一次吗
Shall we try this one more time?
A  E
A-E--
F
F--
A  E  I  O  U
A-E-I-O-U--
A
A--
B  C['操蛋'没拼完]
B-C--
行了  我们明白了
Yeah, we-- we got it.
真是太抱歉了
I am-- I am-- I am just so, so sorry.
至少这次他没拉裤子
Well, at least this time he didn't shit himself.
也算是有进步了
Guess that's progress.
喂
Yes.
我们有麻烦了
We may have a problem.
我在毒品管制局外面
I've got eyes on the DEA.
刚有人进去了
They just had a visitor--
是赫克托・塞拉曼加
Hector Salamanca
我都不知道该说什么了
I don't even know what to say to you right now.
你就给我坐在这里
You just sit here,
好好想想
and you think about how far
那种行为会给你带来多大的麻烦吧
that kind of behavior is going to get you.
后果很严重  我告诉你
Not far, let me tell you.
改变主意了吗
Any second thoughts?
那我们开始吧
Then let's get to work.
你好
Hello
平克曼先生
Mr. Pinkman...
你可以走了
you're free to go.
为什么
Why?
怎么了
What happened?
毒检报告出来了
Tox screen came back.
不是蓖麻毒素
No ricin poisoning.
没想到吧
Surprised, huh?
不  怎么会没想到
No, why should I be?
外套别忘了
Your jacket.
后会有期
Till we meet again.
喂  停车
Yo! Right here.
安德莉亚  我只想问问布洛克的情况
Hey, Andrea, I'm just checking on Brock.
这件事好像
Uh, hey, it sounds like--
我是说  给我回电话好吗
I mean, listen, just call me if you can, all right?
我现在就回去
I'm headed back over.
对不起  打扰一下
Hey, excuse me.
喂
Yes.
我们接到平克曼了
We just picked up Pinkman.
没人看见
No witnesses.
赫克托呢
What about Hector?
里外我都查过了
I've checked inside and out.
没有窃听器和摄像头
No wires, no camera,
没人监视
no surveillance.
一小时前有警车巡逻经过
A police cruiser rolled through about an hour ago.
应该只是例行的
Seemed routine.
只有他一个人在房里
It's just him, alone in his room.
很好
All right.
我现在过去
I'm on my way.
这事由我来
Maybe it's better if--
比较好吧
if I do this myself.
我要亲自动手
I do this.
没问题了
It's all clear.
在这里等着
Wait here.
什么人才会去找毒品管制局
What kind of man talks to the DEA?
没人
No man.
完全没有
No man at all.
你这个残废的叛徒
A crippled little rata.
多响亮的名号啊
What a reputation to leave behind.
你想以这样的方式让后人记住你吗
Is that how you want to be remembered?
这是你最后看我的机会了  赫克托
Last chance to look at me, Hector.
天啊
Oh, my God.
天呐
Oh, Jesus.
投票一定是一样的
...the same vote for sure.
你知道吗  又到时间了
Hey, you know what? It's that time again,
我们该播报些你们自己遭遇的惨痛经历了
where we tell you about your own personal slice of hell
现在是"阿尔布开克午后通勤"时间
known as the Albuquerque afternoon commute.
那里情况有多糟
How bad are things looking out there?
告诉你们  这时候就在往南25公里处
I'll tell you what. Right now southbound 25
在杰弗逊街右路肩发生了一起事故
has got an accident there at Jefferson on the right shoulder,
所以车辆行径那片区域时
so make sure you stay to the left
请保持靠左行驶
as you move through that area,
在大"I"字形路口请减速行驶
and things have slowed to a crawl at the Big I,
在那里千万小心
no surprises there, either.
好的  等等
All right, hang on.
我不得不打断你一下
I hate to interrupt you here,
我有条爆炸性新闻
but I do have some breaking news here,
来自北方山谷
now coming out of the North Valley, apparently.
据报道  有家私人养老院发生了爆炸案
An explosion has been reported at a nursing home,
名叫卡萨・特拉奇拉老院
the Casa Tranquila Nursing Home.
-不是吧  -你听说过那地方
- Oh, no. - You heard of that place.
很遗憾  目前为止还不清楚具体情况
We've got very few details on it so far,unfortunately.
最初报道的是
The initial report is, though,
遇难者多达三人
that as many as three people may have been killed.
天呐
Oh, no.
这则新闻令人不安
Now, the news is disturbing.
一旦有新消息
We're going to get you more information on this
我们会及时播报
just as soon as it comes in.
我能想象  那边情况相当棘手
Situation over there, I imagine, is pretty hectic.
-那里交通情况怎么样  -好
- What's traffic looking like? - Yeah,
我知道那家养老院在哪里
I know where the nursing home is.
如果你们路过那片区域
If you're moving through that area,
我们准备说的是东向西行的车道
we're going to be talking about east and westbound Paseo
就是在北方山谷的那片区域
in that area there in the North Valley.
如果你要穿过那里  请绕开那片区域
Please, you've got to avoid that area as you move through.
我们深切悼念这起事故的死者
Our hearts going out to the victims of this tragedy.
我们会第一时间播报本次事故的详尽信息
We'll bring you more details just as soon as we get them.
欢迎收听小野狼102.5调频
Coming up on Coyote 102.5--
史密斯飞船  戴夫・莱帕德
Aerosmith, Def Leppard.
请锁定本台的新墨西哥台的"驾车随行"节目
Keep it right here on New Maxico's "Find Us Drive".
你想用断手制毒吗
You wanna cook with a broken arm?
下一步  二氧化碳
Next step, CO2.
做吧
Do it.
最好能让我听到响声
I better hear them click.
怎么了  你不能老实在上面待着吗
What, you got a problem with stairs?
古斯死了
Gus is dead.
我们还有事要做
We've got work to do.
快跑
Vámonos!
他会康复的
Uh, he's going to pull through.
是吗
Yeah?
对  看上去有生命危险
Yeah, it looked kind of touch-and-go
有那么一会儿  可他会...
there for a while, but he's gonna--
他会挺过来
he's gonna make it.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
Oh, thank God.
可医生还是坚持说不是因为蓖麻毒素
You know, still saying it wasn't the ricin.
我不太明白
I don't understand.
还能是什么
Then what was it?
说最可能是因为
Saying it was most likely
一种名叫铃兰的花
a flower called lily of the valley.
对  这种花很常见
Yeah, it's-- it's, like, common.
它含有红色果仁
It's got these red berries on it
味道应该是甜的
that I guess taste sweet,
有时会有小孩子尝鲜
and sometimes little kids eat them
结果就中毒了  就这样
and wind up poisoning themselves, and that's it,
没别的了
nothing more.
所以古斯终究没有给他下毒
So Gus didn't poison him after all.
但他还是...
Still, he--
他还是非死不可  对吧
he had to go, right?
绝对的
You're damn right.
古斯非死不可
Gus had to go.
你知道  我该...
Um, you know, I should--
我该回去了
I should get back.
安德莉亚在等我
Andrea's waiting.
我在卡萨・特拉奇拉养老院
I'm here at Casa Tranquila,
今早这间敬老院发生了爆炸
where three people are dead following an explosion
三人丧生
that rocked this elderly care facility earlier today.
爆炸引发的火球把一件卧室完全烧没了
The fireball completely consumed one resident's room
还损坏了旁边的公共区域
and damaged common areas nearby.
沃尔特
Walt?
沃尔特  我找个安静点的地方听你电话
Walt, let me get somewhere where I can hear you.
告诉他汉克叔叔说的对
Tell him Uncle Hank was right. Shh.
沃尔特
Walt?
你还好吗
How are you doing?
你还问我  你还好吗
How am I doing? How are you doing?
我...
I'm, uh...
我还不错
I'm doing quite well.
很好
I'm good.
天呐  沃尔特  有新闻
Jesus, Walt, the news here.
古斯・福林死了
Gus Fring is dead.
他和一个墨西哥贩毒集团成员
He was blown up along with some person
一起被炸死了
from some Mexican cartel,
毒品管制局也不知道怎么回事
and the DEA has no idea what to make of it.
你知情吗
Do you know about this?
-沃尔特  我要你...  -结束了
- Walt? I need you to - It's over.
我们安全了
We're safe.
是你干的吗
Was this you?
发生什么事了
What happened?
我赢了
I won.